<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Writings.</title>
    <link>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Writings. (books)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 17:16:33 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 17:16:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re Singaporean - read this book. If you live in a world where there are people who could own up to twelve cars (cue Selling Sunset), and also people who might not have a roof over their heads - read this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But be prepared: &lt;strong&gt;reading TIWILL is uncomfortable.&lt;/strong&gt; It offers not only a level of scrutiny over the lives of a group of people often considered &amp;ldquo;invisible&amp;rdquo;, but also a deep examination into the values and preconceptions of the reader.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIWILL is very much a collection of vignettes - providing a peek into multiple dimensions of the lives of the low-income. Teo has (quite consciously, I believe) avoided dramatising these differences - instead, she invites you to step into the smallness, but also the warmth, of the homes of a socio-economic group that is often swept under the carpet. As the reader is immersed in the physical, mental, and emotional spaces in which the low-income operate in daily, he/she is inadvertently forced to challenge his/her understanding (and/or stereotypes) around what poverty looks like, what drives poverty, and why poverty is so difficult to change / eradicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIWILL doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer answers to how the situation for lower-income individuals can be improved - it is, after all, highly complex (something which readers will better appreciate by the end of the book) and this book is not written with the purpose of directing / defining policy. But TIWILL provides exactly the first step we need: to start thinking about who we are, who we &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be, what we want &lt;em&gt;our society&lt;/em&gt; to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Teo writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We who have the power to make choices disproportionately shape outcomes and limit options for those people who don&amp;rsquo;t have the power to make choices.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>