<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings.</title>
    <link>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Writings.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It took 3 years for me to get to this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first started writing on Medium, left it to drift into one of my ideas-never-fully-realised black holes. I then took to Goodreads, initiated a very ambitious 18-book challenge, but ended up with zero entries. On some days, I found it hard to sleep because my mind was running through ideas I had from the day, and how I would flesh them out in writing. But nothing. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was (and am) a perfectionist. I wanted to achieve my ideal - the Atlantics, the Brain Pickings - in one single step. 
Nothing I wrote ever felt &lt;em&gt;good enough&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;looked the part&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;sounded&lt;/em&gt; like the ideals I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding one&amp;rsquo;s voice can be a long journey.
Putting one&amp;rsquo;s thoughts out there on the interwebs does take quite a bit of courage.
But you can&amp;rsquo;t get any better until you put pen to paper, and take that first step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by the approach of design thinking to Think, Make, Break, Repeat - here&amp;rsquo;s my first &lt;em&gt;baby&lt;/em&gt; step.
A collection of short essays / responses to books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, interesting news of the day, and my personal projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy to stay in touch on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/wenyuntan/&#34;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wenyun-tan&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeling away the curtain on poverty in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/posts/01-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/posts/01-book-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re Singaporean - read this book. If you live in a world where there are people who could own up to twelve cars (cue Selling Sunset), and also people who might not have a roof over their heads - read this book. You will be surprised, challenged, compelled to think, and will keep thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Part 1 of my quest to read more Singaporean literature (fiction and non-fiction alike). After hearing so much about Teo You Yenn&amp;rsquo;s much raved about book &amp;ldquo;This Is What Inequality Looks Like&amp;rdquo; - I had to add it to the list. The verdict - a very solid five stars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But be prepared: &lt;strong&gt;reading TIWILL is uncomfortable.&lt;/strong&gt; It offers not only a level of scrutiny over the lives of a group of people often considered &amp;ldquo;invisible&amp;rdquo;, but also a deep examination into the values and preconceptions of the reader. The book achieves the same effect that I believe Parasite did for many viewers - introducing an undercurrent of thinking, generating more thoughts with yet another observation of something (an object, a person, an activity). Previously innocuous, but now laden with meaning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIWILL is very much a collection of vignettes - providing a peek into multiple dimensions of the lives of the low-income. Teo has (quite consciously, I believe) avoided dramatising these differences - instead, she invites you to step into the smallness, but also the warmth, of the homes of a socio-economic group that is often swept under the carpet. As the reader is immersed in the physical, mental, and emotional spaces in which the low-income operate in daily, he/she is inadvertently forced to challenge his/her understanding (and/or stereotypes) around what poverty looks like, what drives poverty, and why poverty is so difficult to change / eradicate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TIWILL doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer answers to how the situation for lower-income individuals can be improved - it is, after all, highly complex (something which readers will better appreciate by the end of the book) and this book is not written with the purpose of directing / defining policy. But TIWILL provides exactly the first step we need: to start thinking about who we are, who we &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to be, what we want &lt;em&gt;our society&lt;/em&gt; to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Teo writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We who have the power to make choices disproportionately shape outcomes and limit options for those people who don&amp;rsquo;t have the power to make choices.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are on Goodreads, the same review can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/review/show/3341040591?book_show_action=false&amp;amp;from_review_page=1&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surgery on the brain of a neurosurgeon</title>
      <link>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/posts/02-book-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wenyun-tan.github.io/blog/posts/02-book-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I try not to give away too much on my book reviews (especially since they go onto Goodreads and qualifying everything with &lt;em&gt;spoilers&lt;/em&gt; is a chore). But I especially loved this very personal journey into the mind of one of Britain&amp;rsquo;s greatest neurosurgeons - his triumphs, his failures, and the emotional turmoil behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a very refreshing genre for me - I&amp;rsquo;ve had my fair share of medical TV dramas but not dived into books like these. Another major draw is the context in which this book is situated - the field of neurosurgery, which is still very much a fascinating black box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry Marsh writes wonderfully: he has a strong and distinctive voice that tells you as it is - not only about his experiences, but also who he is as a person, unabashedly. (Whether you think you might like the man as a friend or colleague is a separate matter altogether.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through this very real and personal account, Marsh achieves the objective he established at the beginning of the book - reminding us as readers that doctors are not as superhuman as we make them to be, and they too go through very human challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S. A very timely read as our medical workers on the frontlines are working tirelessly and doing their best to keep us all safe in COVID-19 times. Show your appreciation where you can!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>